Harry Turnbull

Twitter: @hturnbull | Email: hturnbull@live.co.uk | GitHub: github.com/hturnbull93 | Blog: medium.com/@hturnbull93

I am a Front End developer, looking for new opportunities to work with a team of passionate, smart people, working to build useful apps that consumers enjoy using.

I am self-trained and have been working as a freelancer for the past three years. I'm passionate about the intersection of technology and creativity. This led me to train at Makers Academy (London's leading programming bootcamp), to learn best practices, tools and methodologies, and become a professional Front End Developer.

I'm looking for opportunities where I can continue to learn, challenge myself and work with great people to build amazing things.

Skills

Team-Focused - During my final project at Makers, we took on React. As the most experienced React developer, I took it upon myself to help my team fill any knowledge gaps. I did this by discussing examples I had created with them to test their knowledge of the technology. This accelerated our development greatly.

Project Organisation - At Makers we often worked in groups on larger scale projects using XP/Agile methodologies and task tracking methodologies such as Kanban.

Using these techniques I led the Mission-Ctrl project team through a sprint with the aim to refactor the entire codebase, going from 31 tests with 66% code coverage to 57 tests with 97% coverage, a significant improvement.

Communication - When communicating with non-technical stakeholders, translating technical details to and from less technical terms is key. Additionally, I have successfully used my ability to communicate, and my experience of good UX/UI design, to persuade clients away from features that would annoy users.

I believe the best way to know if you truly understand something is to communicate it clearly to someone else. With that in mind I maintain a Medium blog of things I learn and want to share my understanding of.

Technical Knowledge - I have worked with a variety of languages, technologies and softwares:

Languages Ruby, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Technologies Rails, Sinatra, Node.js, Express, jQuery, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB,

TravisCl, Heroku, Surge

Testing RSpec, Capybara, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Jest, Enzyme

Frameworks

Concepts XP/Agile methodology, TDD/BDD, Object Oriented Design, Remote

working, Pair programming, Continuous Integration & Deployment, Git

workflow, Code review, MVC Pattern, RESTful APIs

Tools VSCode, Git, Figma, Photopea (FOSS alternative to Photoshop),

Postman, Windows 10, Linux (Ubuntu), OSx

Hobbies and Interests

Improvised comedy - I perform live on stage with no script, based on audience suggestion. Skills from improv have great applications in the workplace too, such as active listening, generating ideas, building trust within teams, and working out of joy instead of fear.

Cycling - I enjoy cycling, especially e-bikes.

Running - I run to keep fit, and sometimes I enjoy it.

Projects

Mission-Ctrl - Group project. An arcade style game to learn VSCode shortcuts.

Bank Tech Test - A CLI program emulating a bank account, showcasing test driven development in 3 languages.

Neogram - A social media photo sharing web-app, inspired by instagram and neomorphism design.

Bowling Scorecard - An immersive bowling scorecard.

News Summary - A single page web app consuming the Guardian API, using vanilla HTML, CSS, and JS.

Experience

The Nursery Theatre Ltd (Nov 2017 to Present) Digital Communication and Website Manager

Graphic and Web Designer (Aug 2017 to Present)

Freelance

Freedom Tech Ltd (Nov 2015 to Jul 2017) Marketing and Project Manager

Education

Makers Academy (Feb 2020 to Jun 2020) A 16 week intensive programming bootcamp

FreeCodeCamp (2018 - Present) Responsive Web Design Certification

University of Nottingham (Sep 2011 to Jun 2015) MSci Life Sciences, 2:1